# Carlos Torres Moral



#### **CONTACT DATA**

- (+34) 644 320 094
- Barcelona (08004)
- in /carlostorrxs

#### **ABOUT ME**

- Spanish nationality
- **±** 28 years old (07/07/1994)
- Full driving license
- \* References available upon request

I bring a unique blend of backgrounds in political science, linguistics, and now, programming.

As a political scientist, I honed my research and analytical skills through report writing, policy assessment, data retrieval, and broad perspective problem-solving.

As a Spanish teacher, I've immersed myself in various cultures, understanding first-hand the impact of cultural nuances on larger organizations.

Recently, my career took an exciting turn when I transitioned into a role that combines my analytical expertise with my interest in programming. Initially just a hobby leveraged at work, it soon became an obsession and recently my role evolved to automate workflows and enhance productivity across multiple teams full-time.

Driven by curiosity in back-end development, I've recently completed a back-end bootcamp, augmenting my frontend skills gained on the job.

Should you require any further information, please do not hesitate to contact me.

## **LANGUAGES**

Spanish and Catalan:

Native

English:

C1 Advanced English (CAE) Credential ID 500/2598/3 Score 193/210

## **SOFTWARE**

- Intermediate knowledge of Javascript, HTML and CSS. Basic knowledge of Python, SQL, and Java with Spring Boot.
- Experience with WordPress and cPanel (I built a website on my own).
- Experience using Zoom as a host and managing online meetings, as a Spanish teacher.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

SPS Associate CS Andon Cord (full-time programmer) - Amazon

March 2022 - Now

After a year of providing consistent value and innovation, my role evolved to exclusively focus on web front-end developing, to enhance productivity in a team where speed is a critical factor.

- Leveraging internal Amazon APIs to drive efficiency by automating manual work.
- Revolutionizing workflows for Quality Audits, Metrics, and other specific processes, resulting in significant productivity increases.
- o Addressing my team's technical issues, by developing alternate solutions.
- Providing assistance to external teams.
- Pioneering an unprecedented role with full autonomy, working with more than 6 projects simultaneously, learning how to manage time and prioritize.
- Very focused on modern Javascript's (ES6) features and its best practices.
- Employing Python and advanced Excel (PowerQuery, macros) to perform business processes.

# SPS Associate CS Andon Cord - Amazon

January 2022 - March 2023

Core responsibilities:

- Researching customer inquiries & inventory discrepancies to identify root causes of customer dissatisfaction peaks and ensure the accuracy of product data, liaising with internal departments and external vendors to ensure proper resolutions.
- o Working on multiple additional projects using Javascript.

### Spanish Teacher - Freelance

July 2019 - January 2022

Teaching of face-to-face and online courses in the following academies:

- Keiko's Dream (july 2019 june 2021): teached business Spanish to the employees of a French digital company.
- Unaffiliated (march 2020 january 2022): teached Spanish to managers and digital profesionals living in Barcelona, from beginners to advanced. Some reviews available at apprentus.com/in/carlostorres.
- Deliberate Spanish (may 2021 december 2021): teached general Spanish through online lessons, correction of texts and audios, providing feedback and stimulating conversations inforums; with mainly American students.
- Academic Intern Atlas Language School (Dublin)

June 2018 - September 2018

Administrative support within the Academic Department of the school. Improved efficiency of student feedback quantitative and qualitative analysis by designing spreadsheets ad hoc.

Research Trainee - Institut de Ciències Polítiques i Socials

October 2015 - April 2016

Support for the «Anuari Politic de Catalunya» report of 2015 (mark: A). My tasks included summary of legal texts, elaboration of databases and electoral data treatment, follow-up of government activity, and press research.

## **EDUCATION**

Java Back-End Web Development Bootcamp - Ironhack

February 2023 - May 2023

- $\circ\,$  Learned the basics of Java, Spring Boot, JPA, SQL (MySQL), and Git.
- Built a Barcelona real estate API allowing users to publish, search, and bookmark offers.

Master's Degree in Spanish as a Foreign Language Didactics - Universidad Antonio de Nebrija

October 2017 - not finished

Pending Master's thesis.

**Bachelor's Degree in Political Science and Public Management** - Universitat Autònoma de Barcelona (UAB)

September 2012 - July 2017

Specialization in International Relations.

# **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

Volunteer - WWOOF (United Kingdom)

July 2016 - August 2016

Worked with two organic farms and social service providers for disabled people in Mal-mesbury and Chedington.

Boy Scout - Acció Escolta

September 2000 - August 2013

Growing up as a scout, I have internalized certain values and I have assumed several civil and educational responsibilities. I have also been in charge of 6 to 18 year old children.